I'll get candles and my mom's lace tablecloth.
我帶蠟燭跟我媽的蕾絲桌布
And since it's Rachel's birthday...
既然是瑞秋的生日…
...I thought I'd poach a salmon.
…我想我煮一條鮭魚
What?
怎麼樣嘛？
Question. Why do we always have parties where you poach things?
我要問為什麼每次開派對 你都要水煮東西啊？
You want to be on the food committee?
你想總掌食物委員會嗎？
Question 2. Why do we always have parties with committees?
問題二，為什麼每次派對 都要有食物委員會？
Why can't we just get pizza and beer and have fun?
為什麼不買些披薩跟啤酒 大家高興就好了嘛？
I agree. Fancy parties are only fun if you're fancy on the inside.
我認為花俏的派對 是給打心底花俏的人的
And I'm not sure we are.
我們又不是這種人
You don't want it to be special?
你們不想要點特別的？
Fine. You can throw any kind of party you want.
很好，你們愛怎麼樣就怎麼樣
Joey,they're not real!
喬伊，那是假的
I start miles beneath the surface of these things. They're fake.
我這裡面空空如也
See? Honk,honk!
看，空空
Wow,it's like porno for clowns!
像給小丑看的小電影
The One With Two Parties
-=BT之家DRM小組 http://bbs.btbbt.com=- 河馬壓縮製作 本字幕為河馬根據R3DVD OCR得來
六人行 第2季 第22集 一個頭兩個大
Neither of Rachel's sisters can come.
我跟瑞秋的妹妹講了 她們都不能夠來
I still have to invite Dylan and Emma and Shannon Cooper.
那我還得邀請迪倫 艾瑪，還有古香濃
No Shannon Cooper.
不要香濃
Why not her?
為什麼呢？
Because she....
因為她…
She steals stuff.
會偷東西
Or maybe she doesn't and Joey slept with her and never called her back.
又或許她不會偷東西，但他跟 她上床後就沒再打電話給她了
Joey,that is horrible.
喬伊，那太過份了
Hey,I liked her.
我喜歡她，好嗎？
Maybe too much.
或許太喜歡了
I don't know.
我不知道
I guess I just got scared.
我猜我只是怕了
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
對不起，我不知道
I didn't think anyone would buy that. Okay!
沒想到有人會吃這一套
Hi,honey. How did it go?
蜜糖，好玩嗎？
It was the graduation from hell.
地獄的畢業典禮
My cousin went to hell on a football scholarship.
我表弟是靠足球獎學金 上「地獄大學」的
It's supposed to be a joyous occasion.
這本來應該是個快樂的場合
Nobody thought my sister would graduate from college.
我妹妹從大學畢業了 誰也沒想到
It's a testament to what a girl from Long lsland will do for a Celica.
真正證明了一個長島女孩 為了一部車會做什麼
What happened?
到底怎麼了？
My parents happened.
我寶貝父母呀
All they had to do was sit in the same stadium,smile...
他們只需要坐在同一個體育館 驕傲地微笑…
...and not talk about the divorce. But no!
…絕口不提離婚的事 但不！
They got into a fight during the commencement address.
開幕致詞到一半時 他們就吵得不可開交了
Bishop Tutu actually had to stop and shush them.
主教還得停下來 叫他們兩個住口
You know the good news?
你們知道好消息是什麼嗎？
I get to serve coffee for the next eight hours.
我接著可以幫人 倒八小時的咖啡
I guess we don't invite her parents.
那我們可以不要邀請她父母
-How about just her mom? -Why her mom?
只邀她媽媽，怎麼樣？ 為什麼？
Because I already invited her.
因為我已經邀了
Did you ask Stacy Roth?
你邀了史戴西嗎？
Can't invite her.
不，不能邀她
She also steals.
她也會偷東西
Here are the candles. Where's the birthday cake?
這是生日蛋糕的蠟燭 那生日蛋糕呢？
We're not having birthday cake.
我們不吃生日蛋糕
We're having birthday flan.
我們吃生日派餅
Excuse me?
什麼？
It's a traditional Mexican custard dessert.
是一種傳統墨西哥軟凍點心
That's nice.
不錯呀
Happy birthday,Rachel. Here's some goo!
生日快樂，瑞秋，來些膏
Dr. Greene!
林醫生
Oh,my God! It's Rachel's dad.
老天啊，是瑞秋的爸爸
Why are you here?
你來做什麼？
The father can't see the daughter on her birthday?
怎麼了？女兒生日 老爸過來看看也不行嗎？
No,no,the father can.
不…老爸當然可以
But since I am the roommate, I can tell you she's not here.
但是由於我是她室友 我可以告訴你她不在
And I'll pass along the message. Okay? So bye-bye.
我會轉告她你來過了 所以，拜拜
You're having a party.
你們開派對呀
No,no,not a party.
不，不是派對啦
Just a surprise gathering of some people Rachel knows.
只是一群 瑞秋認識的人的驚喜聚會
-This is Phoebe,Chandler and Joey. -I'll never remember all that.
這是菲比，錢德，喬伊 太多人了我記不住
So what's the deal?
所以你們是要…瑞秋回來
Rachel comes home,people pop out and yell stuff? Is that it?
大家跳出來尖叫 是不是這樣子？
This isn't your first surprise party,is it,sir?
這不是 你的第一個驚喜派對吧？
Hi,Monica.
摩妮卡
The Chinese menu guy. Forgot the menus.
有人送了中餐館菜單來 他忘了菜單了
So basically,just a Chinese guy.
所以基本上只是個中國人而已
Dr. Greene,come with me. We'll put your jacket on Rachel's bed.
林醫生，你跟我來好了 我們把外套放瑞秋床上
All right. That sounds like a two-person job.
好啊，那似乎需要兩個人
Well,my goodness! What was that?
我的天，你剛幹嘛你？
Sandra,I thought you were Rachel. We weren't ready for you yet.
真對不起，我以為你是瑞秋 可是我們還沒準備好
-You thought I was Rachel? -Yes,because you look so young.
你以為我是瑞秋？ 對啊，你看起來好年輕
And because you're both, you know,white women.
而且基本上你們兩個都是… 白種女人
Oh,I missed you kids. Should I put my coat in the bedroom?
我好想念你們 我應該把外套放房間嗎？
-No,I'll take that for you. -Oh,well,thank you.
不，交給我好了 那就謝了
Such a gentleman. Thank you.
真是個紳士啊
It all looks so nice. So festive. All the balloons.
看起來真棒，喜氣洋洋的 那麼多汽球
Oh,the funniest thing happened to me on the way here.
我過來的時候碰見一兩件怪事
-I was driving -That's great!
我在開… 太棒了
I can't wait to hear the rest, but I have to go to the bathroom.
我等不及你說完 我快憋不住了
Hey,come with me.
跟我來
-What? -lt will be like we're gal pals.
什麼？ 就像我們是姐妹
You know,like at a restaurant. It'll be fun! Come on.
你知道，像在餐廳 會很好玩的，來吧…
Oh,my God. Oh,my God. Oh,my God!
天啊…
Think. Think.
想一想，快想一想
What would Jack and Chrissy do?
傑克跟克麗會怎麼做？
Okay,now that your coat is safely in the bed
你的外套安全上床了…
We can come back out in the living room.
我們現在可以回客廳了
Joey and Chandler,it's time you take Dr. Greene over to your place.
對了，喬伊，錢德，我想你們 應該帶林醫生到你們那邊去
Yes,absolutely.
對，完全正確
Why,again?
為什麼？
Because that's where the party is,you goon!
因為派對在那邊呀，呆子
-See,this is just the staging area. -Right,it's the staging area.
這邊只是準備區 對…準備區而已
This is clearly in the wrong apartment.
這個放錯地方了
All right,you guys are off to party number one.
好吧，你們這些去一號派對
And you....
而你們呢…
You are off to party number two.
去二號派對
All right,let's keep it moving, let's keep it moving.
繼續走，繼續走，快
At least send some women to my party.
你至少送些女的來我這邊好嗎
Okay,that's Ross. All right.
是羅斯，好…
Okay,they're coming.
他們來了
Thank you for such a wonderful dinner.
謝謝你美妙的晚餐
Thanks for being born.
謝謝你出生
Thank you for my beautiful earrings. They're perfect.
謝謝你這對漂亮的耳環 真的好美
I love you.
我愛你
Now,you can exchange them if you want,okay?
你要的話可以拿去換
Now I love you even more.
現在我更愛你了
Surprise!
驚喜…
Oh,my gosh!
天啊…
Wow!
哇！
Oh,my God. Mom!
天啊…媽
This is so great!
太棒了
Happy birthday,sweetie.
生日快樂，瑞秋
You! I had no idea!
你…我完全不知
-Really? -No,I knew.
真的？ 不，我知道的
All right.
好
There's food and drinks on the table.
各位，桌上有吃的跟喝的
Go across the hall. Right now,Joey and Chandler's.
現在去對面 喬伊跟錢德那邊，去呀
-Why? -Just go.
為什麼？ 去就是了
Weird.
怪啊
Surprise!
驚喜！
Happy birthday,sweet pea.
生日快樂，小甜豆
Daddy!
爸爸
Both of them are here? Both of them? Both of them are here?
他們都來了，兩個都來了？
Well,we could count again?
我們可以再算一次
I can't believe this!
我無法相信有這種事
You know,this is ridiculous.
這太荒唐了
This is your birthday,your party.
這是你的生日，你的派對
Let's put them together. If they can't deal with it,who cares?
我說把他們放在一起，如果 他們應付不來的話，誰在乎？
-I do. -That's who.
我在乎 就是你
Are you gonna be okay?
你不要緊吧？
I don't really have a choice. I can look at the bright side.
我根本就別無選擇嘛 我可以往好的方面想啊
I get two birthday parties and two birthday cakes.
我有兩個生日派對 還有兩個生日蛋糕
Well,actually...
其實只有…
...just one birthday flan.
…一個生日派餅
It's a traditional Mexican custard dessert.
那是一種墨西哥軟凍點心
Talk to Monica. She's on the food committee.
你去跟摩妮卡講比較好 她是食物委員會的人
Some girl just walked up to me and said,"I want you,Dennis"...
有個女的剛剛走過來跟我說 「我要你，丹尼」…
...and stuck her tongue down my throat.
…然後給了我一個熱吻
I love this party!
我愛這個派對
-Quick volleyball question. -Volleyball.
我有個排球問題 排球？
We set up a court in your room.
我們在你房間弄了個球場
You didn't like that gray lamp,did you?
你不是真的喜歡 那個灰燈，對不對？
A woman stuck her tongue down my throat. I'm not even listening to you.
剛才有個女人給我一個熱吻 我根本就沒聽你說話
-Dennis! -Okay,that's me.
丹尼… 她在叫我了
Can you keep Dad occupied? I'm gonna talk to Mom for a while.
蜜糖，你陪我爸一下，好嗎？ 我要去跟我媽講一下話
Do you have any ideas for any openers?
那我用什麼話當… 當開場白
Stay clear of "I'm the guy that's doing your daughter"...
你只要避開「我是那個上 你女兒的人」…
...and you should be okay.
…就不會有問題了
I want you to take a piece of paper
我要你們一個人拿一張紙…
Here you go. And write down your most embarrassing memory.
拿去 然後寫下你們最臭的回憶
When you're not using the markers, put the caps back on them...
請各位在用完麥克筆之後 把筆蓋蓋上…
... because they will dry out.
…不然的話，筆會幹掉的
Hi,Dr. Greene.
林醫生
So how's everything in the...
血管外科遊戲中…
...vascular surgery...
…的一切…
...game?
…都還好嗎？
It's not a game,Ross. A woman died on my table today.
那不是遊戲，羅斯 今天有個女人死在我手術台上
I'm sorry.
很遺憾
That's the good thing about my job.
那就是我工作的好處
All the dinosaurs on my table are already dead.
因為我在工作台上的那些恐龍 都已經死了
Listen,I don't mean to be a pain about this...
聽著，各位 我並不是故意要煩你們的…
... but I've noticed some of you are just placing them on.
…但我注意到 你們剛剛有些人只是套上
You want to push the caps...
你們應該是要用力按…
... until you hear them click.
…按到喀的一聲為止
Gunther!
阿剛
Where you going?
你要去哪裡啊？
I was sort of thinking about maybe
我…我只是在想，或許我…
No! No,you can't go! No,this is fun.
不…你不能走 不，這很好玩
We're just starting. Here's your marker.
來嘛…我們才剛開始 來，這是你的筆
If you want to go,just go.
聽著，你想走就走好了
She'll yell at me again.
不，她會再吼我
All right,I can get you out.
好吧，我可以把你弄出去
What?
什麼？
In a minute,I'll create a diversion.
等一下我們來個聲東擊西
When I do,walk quickly to the door and don't look back.
到時候，你趕快朝門走 不要回頭
-I think I need a drink. -I'll get it for you.
我想來杯喝的 我去幫你拿
-What do you want? -Scotch.
你要喝什麼？ 威士忌
I'll be back in 10 seconds with your scotch on the rocks in a glass.
好，我十秒鐘之內 會帶著你的威士忌加冰塊回來
Neat!
純
Cool.
正
Neat,as in no rocks.
純的，不加冰塊
I know.
我知道
Hello,Ross! Where have you been?
羅斯，你上哪兒去了？
I have been in the bathroom.
我一直在洗手間
Stay clear of the salmon mousse.
避開那些鮭魚慕斯
Scotch neat.
純威士忌
That's Rachel's father's drink.
瑞秋她爹就愛那玩意兒
Mine too. Isn't that neat?
我也是，很酷，不是嗎？
Scotch neat.
純威士忌
Would you excuse me?
我先失陪了
Where are you sneaking off to,mister?
你想溜到哪裡去呢，先生？
I'm getting my cigarettes.
我要去拿我外套裡的香煙
No.
不…
What do you mean "no"?
什麼意思啊？
See,because that's the staging area.
因為那邊是準備區
You go in there,it'll ruin the whole illusion of the party.
你一去的話 你對派對的幻影就都成空了
Take your scotch back in there...
你還是帶著你的威士忌回去…
...and I will get your cigarettes for you,sir.
…然後我去幫你拿香煙 好嗎？
-Get my glasses too. -All righty-roo.
還有我的眼鏡 有我就搞定了
What a great moment to say that for the first time.
真是第一次說那句話的好時機
Okay,the first person's most embarrassing memory is...
我現在來看看 第一個人的最臭的回憶就是…
... "Monica,your party sucks."
…「摩妮卡，你的派對真遜」
Very funny.
非常幽默
Oh,no! Did someone forget to use a coaster?
天啊，有人忘了用杯墊嗎？
What?
什麼？
I don't see anything.
我沒有看到呀
Great,I'm seeing water rings again.
是嗎？我的眼睛又花了
Ross,whose glasses are those?
羅斯，那是誰的眼鏡啊？
Mine.
我的
You wear bifocals?
你戴遠近兩用的眼鏡？
I have a condition apparently...
我的視力…
...that I require...
…顯然同時…
...two different sets of focals.
…需要用到兩種鏡片
Do you know my husband has glasses just like that?
你知道我先生也有一副 跟你一樣的眼鏡嗎？
Well,those are very popular frames.
那副鏡框很流行
Neil Sedaka wears them.
尼爾席達卡也有一副
I hear you can get people out of here.
聽說你有辦法弄我們出去 是不是？
You didn't tell me your boyfriend smokes.
你並沒有告訴我你男友會抽煙
Yeah,like a chimney.
對，像根煙囪
Big smoker.
大煙槍
Big,big smoker.
超大煙槍
In fact,I'm gonna go into the hallway and fire up this bad boy.
事實上，我現在就去走廊上 點燃這根大壞蛋了
Are you wearing my glasses?
你在戴我的眼鏡嗎？
Yes.
對
I was just warming up the earpieces for you.
我只是在替你 把那個耳架弄暖一點
Thank you.
謝謝
Is that one of my cigarettes?
那是我的香煙嗎？
Yes,it is. I was just moistening the tip.
對，沒錯 我在把這個煙屁股弄濕
She's taking the trash out, so I can get you out of here.
好了，她去倒垃圾了 我可以弄你們出去了
But it has to be now. She'll be back any minute.
可是你們得馬上走 她隨時會回來
What about my friend?
那我朋友呢？
Only the three of you. Any more and she'll get suspicious.
不行，只有你們三個 超過三個她就會起疑心的
-Let me just get my coat. -There isn't time!
好吧，我去拿外套 沒有時間了
Just leave everything.
什麼都不要拿
They'll take care of you next door.
隔壁那些人會照顧你們的
Is it true they have beer?
他們有啤酒是真的嗎？
Everything you've heard is true.
你聽到的都是真的
Could you guys please keep it down?
你們小聲一點，好不好？
We're trying to start a Boggle tournament.
我們要來個文字遊戲錦標賽
You!
你
And you.
還有你
You're supposed to be at my party.
你們應該在我的派對的啊
And Gunther!
還有阿剛
What are you doing here?
你在這個地方幹什麼啊？
Welcome to the fo
歡迎光臨…
All right,I'm sorry. But these people needed me.
好吧，對不起嘛 可是這些人需要我啊
They work hard all week. It's Saturday night.
他們辛苦了一個禮拜 今天是週末
They deserve to have a little fun. Go!
他們有權享一點兒樂的，去
You know,my party is fun.
我的派對很好玩
It's a little quieter, less obvious sort of fun.
或許是安靜了一點吧 比較含蓄的樂趣
But if people would just give it a chance,it's
但如果大家給它一個機會 那會比較…
-You want me to see a therapist? -Sweetheart,you have a problem.
你要我去看心理醫生？ 親愛的，你顯然有問題了
You've chosen a boyfriend exactly like your father.
你居然選了一個 跟你爸一模一樣的男朋友
Okay,Mom,I'll make an appointment.
媽，我會先去掛號的
But right now,I gotta go. I gotta go do a thing.
現在我得走了 我得去做一件事
Did you know your mother spent $1200 on bonsai trees?
你知道嗎？你老媽居然花了 一千二百塊買一個盆栽
I felt like Gulliver.
我覺得我好像巨人在小森林裡
Daddy,I really want to hear more about this...
爸，你知道嗎？ 我真的很想再多聽，真的…
...but I just have to do some stuff.
…但我有點事要處理
You work and you work and you work at a marriage...
我一直很努力 想要挽救我們的婚姻…
... but all he cares about is his stupid boat.
…可是他只關心他那艘蠢船
You work and you work and you work on a boat.
我一直一直努力的去弄我的船
He always ridiculed my pottery classes.
他老是嘲笑我的燒陶課
And you sand it and varnish it.
磨好了之後還要上釉
But when all is said and done, he still drinks out of the mugs.
但他還是用我做的杯子喝東西
One night of her yoga and Bridges of Madison County....
聽她念一晚她的瑜珈 還有她的「麥迪遜之橋」…
-The scotch,the cigarettes.... - The bonsais and the Chihuahua....
威士忌，香煙… 盆栽和吉娃娃狗…
I may have only been in therapy for three weeks now but
我或許只看了 三個禮拜的心理醫生，但…
What the hell does she want with half a boat?
她要半條船幹什麼？
Okay,okay,you can be shirts and I'll be skins.
你衣服留著我光著身子好了
I'll be skins!
我光身子呀
How you holding up there,tiger?
你沒事吧，老虎？
Sorry. When my parents were getting divorced,I got a lot of "tigers."
很抱歉，我父母在鬧離婚時 很多人叫我「老虎」
I got a lot of "champs," "chiefs," "sports."
很多人叫我 「冠軍」「老大」「君子」
I even got a "governor."
還有人叫我「州長」
This is it,isn't it? This is what my life will be like.
就這樣了，是不是？ 我的生活就會變成這樣
My mom there,my dad there.
我媽跟我爸一人一個地方
Thanksgiving,Christmas.
感恩節，聖誕節
She gets the house,he's in a condo my sister will decorate with wicker.
她得到房子，他住在我妹用 柳條傢俱幫他佈置的公寓
How did you get through this?
錢德，你是怎麼熬過來的？
I relied on a carefully regimented program...
我利用了我精心策劃的計劃…
...of denial...
…拒絕面對現實…
...and wetting the bed.
…還有尿床
You know,I just It's so weird.
這太詭異了
I mean,I was in there just listening to them bitch about each other.
我是說，我人在裡面 卻聽著他們兩個人罵來罵去
All I kept thinking about was the Fourth of July.
可是心裡卻一直在想著國慶日
Because it reminded you of the way...
因為那讓你想起我們的祖先…
...our forefathers used to bitch at each other?
…從前也是罵來罵去的嗎？
It's just this thing. Every year we would...
是這樣子的啦 我們每年…
...go out on my dad's boat and watch the fireworks.
…都會坐我爸的船出海 去看煙火
Mom always hated it because the ocean air made her hair all big.
可是我媽討厭去 因為海風會把她的頭髮吹膨
My sister Jill would be throwing up over the side...
我妹妹吉兒 則會靠在船邊嘔吐…
...and Dad would be upset because nobody helped.
…我爸會不高興 因為沒有人幫他忙
And when we did help,he'd scream at us for doing it wrong.
當我們幫忙的時候呢 他又會吼叫說我們越幫越忙
But then when the fireworks started, everybody just shut up.
但是當煙火開始的時候 大家都閉嘴了
You know,and it'd get really cold.
然後天氣會變得很冷
And we'd all just sort of smoosh under this one blanket.
我們會全部都擠在 一條毯子下面
It never occurred to anybody to bring another one.
從來沒有人想到要多帶一條來
And now it's....
但是現在…
Yeah,I know.
對，我知道
Thanks for coming. I hope you had fun.
謝謝光臨，希望你們玩得開心
All right,I'm hitting the road.
好了，我要走了
Now,I've left my 10 verbs on the table.
我把十個動詞放在你桌上了
Be sure and send me that finished poem.
一定要把完成的詩寄給我
Okay,will do. Glad you came.
我會的，很高興你來了
-I think I saw Rachel out in the hall. -Let me go check.
我想我看到瑞秋在走廊上 我去看看
Your mom wants to say goodbye.
你媽要跟你道別了
Happy birthday,sweetie.
生日快樂，親愛的
You drive safe.
小心開車
What are you doing?
羅斯，你在幹嘛？
I'm getting ready for the water skiing.
我正在為去滑水做準備
Okay,big hug. One more. Come on!
來呀，抱抱
How are you?
你好嗎？
-Where are you going? -To get my coat.
林醫生，你要去哪裡？ 拿我的外套
We'll get that for you.
我們去拿
All right,all right. I can get my own coat.
好了…我可以自己去，好嗎？
Sorry,we're on a major flan high.
抱歉，派餅讓我們爽歪了
Oh,no. No,you're not supposed to be here.
不對…你不應該來這裡的
This is the staging area. It's all wrong. You should leave.
因為這裡是準備區 全弄錯了，你應該走
You know,just get out.
出去就是了
Or perhaps you'd like a creme de menthe.
要不要來杯薄荷酒啊？
I have to be heading toward my chateau.
我必須打道回府了，謝了
I guess we're going back into the hallway again.
好吧，那麼我猜 我們又要回到走廊了
Thanks for coming,Mrs. Greene.
謝謝光臨，林太太
You take care.
保重了
Oh,you kids.
你們這些孩子
Well.
這麼嘛…
This is the best party I've been to in years.
好久沒有參加這麼棒的派對了
Thank you!
謝謝
Okay,everybody, it's time for flan!
各位，切派餅了
Yep! Get ready for the gelatinous fun.
對，準備享用凍凍樂了
Looks like that stuff you get when you get an infection.
看起來有點像 傷口發炎時化的膿
Okay,that's enough.
好了，夠了
Okay,Rachel, make a special flan wish.
瑞秋，許個派餅願吧
Okay,I've got one.
好了
Heads up!
小心！
Wow! Those things almost never come true.
這很少有實現的時候的